The SCOAN Sunday Service
You may be seated. Thank you.
Viewers all over the world, I know you were joining them dancing.
There is nothing anybody can do.
That is your belief.
Your belief is solid.
I say your belief is solid because you are acting on what God has spoken.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
There are some people here that while many here were dancing, they were doing like this.
Why?
They were trying to act on what God had not spoken.
When you are trying to act on what God has not spoken,
you force yourself to believe in what God has not spoken
that is not believing.
You are dreaming, acting on your own imagination.
We need to know God's will and act accordingly.
If I allow you again, you are ready.
So, I have to congratulate you for your belief.
The word belief - believing is simply acting on what God has spoken.
Simple.
It makes believing very simple.
What kind of belief are we talking about?
Many of us spend two to three days in connecting flights - from one country to another.
It is difficult nowadays, it is not easy.
When you fly from one country to another, it is stop-over.
You may spend three days there.
We have many people like that here.
You have paid some price.
God is aware.
I can’t hear you.
Amen.
Yes.
You are actually here because you believe God has promised you.
If your Father promised to give you something and you base your belief on that,
that believing is solid.
I’m not talking of your father at home: I’m talking of God.
If your Father promised you something and you now base your belief on that,
this believing is solid.
This is why we need to know God’s will and act accordingly.
We need to know God’s promise and act according to His will.
If you don’t know God's promise, you want healing and you just say, "God, heal me, heal me",
you may have some problem because you need to know
whether it is the will of God to heal you at that moment or not - before you open your mouth.
We know His will before we pray.
Are you with me?
If you see any prayer that is answered - let there be light and there is light -
the person knows God will bring light before he offers his prayer.
This actually affects our faith.
Today you don’t know whether you’re a man of faith or not. You don’t know.
You consider your relationship with God according to the number of prayers that are answered.
If your prayer is answered, you say, "Oh! God loves me".
God loves everyone.
Hallelujah.
If your Father promised you something and you base your belief on that promise,
this believing is solid.
When your Father has not promised you, you force yourself to believe -
you are not believing but dreaming because you believe in something that is not factual.
I want to take it back again. The word believing is a difficult issue.
Believing is between you and salvation.
Believing is made easy when you know that it is acting on what God has promised,
on what God has said.
That is, you must know His will.
This is why we say, "Let the will of God be done!"
Do you really mean what you are talking about?
If it is the will of God to be done in your life and you want to step out for something,
you must know God will's about it.
It is when you know God’s will that you can act accordingly to His will before you pray.
This is why we need to know God’s will and act accordingly.
It is a prophetic word to your life.
Take it.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
How do you express your belief?
You have not based your belief on what God has said.
You base your belief on what you want, what you are looking for, what you want.
Tell your neighbour.
Not on what God has said or what God will do.
That is why your belief seems to be dreaming.
You know when you’re dreaming of something,
it may happen in one year's time or be a kind of imagination.
Such belief is not factual.
You are dreaming out of your imagination.
This is what is happening to us today.
If God has not promised you something and you force yourself, which today...
If I did not know God’s will, I would have joined you in the kind of prayer you want to offer.
But I’m going to pray according to God’s will.
This is why we are going to receive.
If I shall allow you to offer your prayer, you would continue to force your belief
on what God has not said.
If God has not promised and you force yourself to believe,
such belief is not factual,
you are dreaming out of your imagination.
This is what is happening to us today.
Everything satan tries to bring in order to destroy us is an advantage to us.
If satan brings headache, it’s an opportunity to pray the more.
If satan brings anger, opportunity to move closer to God.
Hallelujah. Rise up! Thank You, Lord.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The way and manner God arranged this ministry:
He arranged it in such a way that it will be very difficult for you to come here without you having faith.
Ninety to ninety-nine have seen the finger of God before they leave.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
In summary again:
God’s promise must be known to us before we pray.
Tell your neighbour.
I can't hear you.
God’s promise must be known to us before we pray.
If not, you will continue to be disappointed.
You will not even know the difference between a miracle and when a strange thing happens.
If you don’t know God’s promise and you offer prayer,
when something strange happens, you call it answer from God.
God’s promise means God’s will.
In the Bible, anywhere you see God’s promise means God’s will.
When we know God's will, we act according to His will.
This is why we say, "Let the will of God be done!"
This is the problem we are facing today.
Simply because we cannot define the word faith.
They cannot.
Faith is a trust that arises out of the fact that the other party is honest, reliable, trustworthy.
It means we are not looking for great faith but great God.
Great God!
Who is that ‘other party’?
Who is reliable in the world?
Who is trustworthy?
It is One that has no beginning and no end that can be trusted.
Faith is a trust that arises out of the fact that the other party is honest, reliable, trustworthy.
Where our trouble lies as a Christian is in the word belief.
The word believe.
And the word faith.
Faith and believe. This is just the problem we have.
There is power in our mouth.
The belief in our heart is released by faith.
"Let there be light!" - to release that power, I need faith to release it.
Faith is a Heavenly resource.
If you need Heavenly resources, it is faith you use.
Like if you need to buy something, you need dollar, naira, rand.
You take money and purchase it.
Now, you want to get Heavenly things like healing, deliverance, all of God's blessings, salvation,
you need faith to purchase them.
They are all Heavenly resources.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
It means that faith can be regarded as a Heavenly currency that purchases Heavenly resources.
It’s not everything that you can buy with 5 dollars.
You can't use 5 dollars to buy things costing 10 dollars.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You now understand the word faith.
Faith is a Heavenly currency.
Tell your neighbour.
What you are able to achieve, depends on the amount of Heavenly currency you have.
The Heavenly resources you are able to receive depend on the Heavenly currencies you have.
You cannot purchase more than what you have.
Faith grows as we continue to read, hear and obey - it grows.
Tell you neighbour: "Allow your faith to grow".
I can't hear you.
Allow your faith to grow
so that you can purchase greater Heavenly resources.
We believe you have been inspired by the clip you have just watched.
Click here to subscribe to witness more of God's power at work in our generation today.